<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on @pwnsyl</title>
		<link>https://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on @pwnsyl</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 13:44:17 +0300</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Technique for layering drum samples. (Mid/Side)</title>
			<link>https://localhost:1313/posts/music/create-depth-in-drum-sounds/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 13:44:17 +0300</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://localhost:1313/posts/music/create-depth-in-drum-sounds/</guid>
			<description>Introduction I discovered this technique while I was trying to create a song only with Ableton&amp;rsquo;s bundled stuff. So I was forced into thinking of alternative ways to create cool sounding hihats.
That basically lead to this layout:
 Dividing the hihat sound into 3 layers.  One channel for the Mid signal Two Channels panned left/right for the sides signal    Controlling the drums ADSR (Attack, Decay, Sustain, Release) will be happeing into the samples itself.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>I discovered this technique while I was trying to create a song only with Ableton&rsquo;s
bundled stuff. So I was forced into thinking of alternative ways to create cool sounding
hihats.</p>
<p>That basically lead to this layout:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dividing the hihat sound into 3 layers.
<ol>
<li>One channel for the Mid signal</li>
<li>Two Channels panned left/right for the sides signal</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Controlling the drums ADSR (Attack, Decay, Sustain, Release) will be happeing into
the samples itself. The goal is to create a similar an cohereant sounding signals.
That resulted into a really nice souding hihat using only the stock samples.</p>
<p>I extened this and created a template layout for layering sounds. Which you can
downloading below.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com">Layering Mid_Side.als</a></p>
<h2 id="breakdown-into-the-layers">Breakdown into the layers:</h2>
<p>Mid&rsquo;s group has an EQ which is set in Mid/Side Mode, where I&rsquo;ve deleted the sides signal.
This channel will be playing only the mid signal.</p>
<p>Sides group is divided into 2 channels both of which are panneld <strong>50L</strong> and <strong>50R</strong></p>
<p>asd</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
